Guide to Miscellaneous Financial Materials Concerning Gold and Silver Mining Companies Operating in the North American West
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Miscellaneous financial materials concerning gold and silver mining companies operating in the North American West
1878-1951
Ndy32
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning gold and silver mining companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, bondholders' agreements, letters to stockholders, prospectuses, reports, advertisements, reprints of journal articles, dividend statements, subscription forms, stock exchange petitions, proxy statements, trust indentures, maps, reorganization notices and agreements, deposit agreements, trust agreements, and balance sheets. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Most of these financial materials were part of a collection acquired by Yale in 1922 from William H. Brown of West Haven, Conn. The collection, initially called the William H. Brown Statistical Library, numbered some 23,000 documents and covered the years 1890 to 1917. The collection was merged with similar materials already in the University Library and later expanded by gifts from Brown and others to become what is now known as the William H. Brown Collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning gold and silver mining companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, bondholders' agreements, letters to stockholders, prospectuses, reports, advertisements, reprints of journal articles, dividend statements, subscription forms, stock exchange petitions, proxy statements, trust indentures, maps, reorganization notices and agreements, deposit agreements, trust agreements, and balance sheets. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically by company name.
Mining corporations -- West (U.S.); Gold mines and mining -- West (U.S.); Silver mines and mining -- West (U.S.); Mining corporations -- Canada, Western; Gold mines and mining -- Canada, Western; Silver mines and mining -- Canada, Western; Proxy statements -- Specimens.; Trust indentures -- Specimens.; William H. Brown Collection
- Alaska-Ebner Gold Mines Company, 1912-1914; Ndy32 U2 +AL11; 3 documents (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alaska Gold Mines Company, 1912-1916; Ndy32 U2 +AL12; 5 documents (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Alaska Juneau Gold Mining Company, 1940-1942; Ndy32 U2 +AL13; 7 documents (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Anaconda Mining & Milling Company, 1935-1937; Ndy32 U2 +An13; 20 documents (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Arizona Silver Mines Company, 1919-1923; Ndy32 U2 +Ar4; 3 documents (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Blenwick Mining Company, 1920?; Ndy32 U2 +B61; 1 document (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Calista Mining Company, 1880; Ndy32 U2 +C1290; 1 document (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Candelaria Mines Company, 1918-1923; Ndy32 U2 +C16
  - Annual Reports, 1921-1923; 3 documents (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Economic aspects, 1918; 1 document (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Carson Hill Gold Mining Company, 1922-1941; Ndy32 U2 +C23; 9 documents (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cerbat Silver Mining and Milling Company, 1919?; Ndy32 U2 +C33; 1 document (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Consolidated Republican Mountain Mining Company, 1878; Ndy32 U2 +C765; 1 document (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Delaware Mines Corporation, 1926; Ndy32 U2 +D376; 12 documents (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Diadem Mining Company, 1919; Ndy32 U2 +D54; 2 documents (Box 1, Folder 14)
- El Paso Consolidated Gold Mining Company, 1913-1916; Ndy32 U2 +EL6; 4 documents (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Eureka-Croesus Mining Company, 1920-1923; Ndy32 U2 +Eu72; 4 documents (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Eureka Smelting Company, 1926; Ndy32 U2 +Eu73; 5 documents (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Federal Mining and Smelting Company, 1905-1927; Ndy32 U2 +F31; 7 documents (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Golden Gate Exploration Company, 1919?; Ndy32 U2 +G56; 2 documents (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Louisiana Consolidated Mining Company, 1918-1921; Ndy32 U2 +L93; 4 documents (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Silver Cliff Mining Company, 1879?; Ndy32 U2 +Si27; 1 document (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Sunshine Mining Company, 1941-1942; Ndy32 U2 +Su74; 2 documents (Box 1, Folder 22)
- United Mines and Trading Company (of New Jersey), 1901?; Ndy32 U2 +Un4; 1 document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- United Rico Mines Company, 1907-1911; Ndy32 U2 +Un43; 8 documents (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Unity Gold Mines Company, 1917?-1924?; Ndy32 U2 +Un95; 3 documents (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Yukon Gold Company, 1909-1951; Ndy32 U2 +Y8; 6 documents (Box 1, Folder 26)